<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Skinly</string>
    <string name="dev_email">equipintelligence@gmail.com</string>

    <string name="download_images_message">
        We need to download a handful of images which would help the application to detect and classify the diseases.
        In order to save the images to your device storage, the application requires the storage permission.
        The downloading will start once the permission is granted.
    </string>
    <string name="continue_image_download_message">
        Images could not downloaded. Would you like to download the images to complete
        the whole process?
    </string>
    <string name="melanoma_result">The app has detected possibilities of Melanoma disease.</string>
    <string name="app_results_disclaimer">The app is in research stage. The actual medical results may vary.</string>
    <string name="no_disease_found_result">No diseases were found in the sample image.</string>

    <string name="download_completed_key">download_complete</string>
    <string name="download_index_key">download_index</string>
    <string name="app_first_open_key">first_open</string>

    <string name="t1">
        <![CDATA[

        <h2><u>What is Melanoma?</u></h2>

        The most dangerous form of skin cancer, these cancerous growths develop when unrepaired DNA damage to
        skin cells (most often caused by ultraviolet radiation from sunshine or tanning beds) triggers mutations
        (genetic defects) that lead the skin cells to multiply rapidly and form malignant tumors. These tumors originate
        in the pigment-producing melanocytes in the basal layer of the epidermis. Melanomas often resemble moles; some
        develop from moles. The majority of melanomas are black or brown, but they can also be skin-colored, pink, red,
        purple, blue or white. Melanoma is caused mainly by intense, occasional UV exposure (frequently leading to sunburn),
        especially in those who are genetically predisposed to the disease.

        <br></br><br></br>

        If melanoma is recognized and treated early, it is almost always curable, but if it is not, the cancer can advance
        and spread to other parts of the body, where it becomes hard to treat and can be fatal. It is not the most
        common of the skin cancers.

        <br></br><br></br>

        ]]>

    </string>
    <string name="t2">
        <![CDATA[


        <h2><u>Symptoms of Melanoma :</u></h2>

        The first sign of melanoma is typically a new spot on the skin, or a change in the size, shape or
        color of an existing mole. The ABCDE method may help you determine whether an abnormal skin growth may be melanoma:

        <br></br><br></br>

        Asymmetry: The mole has an irregular shape.<br></br>
        Border: The edge is not smooth, but irregular or notched.<br></br>
        Color: The mole has uneven shading or dark spots.<br></br>
        Diameter: The spot is larger than the size of a pencil eraser.<br></br>
        Evolving or Elevation: The spot is changing in size, shape or texture.<br></br>
        The only way to be sure if a mole is melanoma is to have it examined by a doctor.<br></br>

        <br></br><br></br>

        <b>Other melanoma symptoms may include:</b>

        <br></br><br></br>

        Sores that do not heal<br></br>
        Pigment, redness or swelling that spreads outside the border of a spot to the surrounding skin<br></br>
        Itchiness, tenderness or pain<br></br>
        Changes in texture, or scales, oozing or bleeding from an existing mole<br></br>
        Blurry vision or partial loss of sight, or dark spots in the iris<br></br>

        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="t3">
        <![CDATA[

        These are examples of they types of treatment available for melanoma.
        Based on your personal history, pathology report, and stage at diagnosis, your doctor may recommend one or
        more of the following:

        <h2><u>Surgery</u></h2>

        Surgery is the mainstay of therapy for early stage melanoma and for the resection of an isolated metastatic
        melanoma site. There are several different types of surgeries that are regularly performed to treat melanoma.

        <h2><u>Radiation</u></h2>

        Radiation therapy uses high energy rays, like x-rays, to kill cancer cells. Although radiation is not an overly
        common melanoma treatment option, it is most often used as a symptom-relieving therapy in patients whose melanoma
        has spread to the brain or bones.

        <h2><u>Clinical Trials</u></h2>

        Clinical trials are research studies to test promising new or experimental cancer treatments.
        There are hundreds of clinical trials happening at any given time, and most experts agree that for
        a late-stage diagnosis, clinical trials are the best treatment option. You can also visit our Clinical
        Trial Finder to learn about clinical trials that are available.

        <br></br><br></br>

        ]]>
    </string>
    <string name="t4">
        <![CDATA[

           <h2><u>Bringing Machine Learning ( ML ) to Android :</u></h2>

        The machine learning model used in this application is built using TensorFlow Python APIs. TensorFlow is a great
        machine learning framework and can run its models on Android as well as on iOS. TensorFlow Lite is an optimum
        API which helps to transform TensorFlow models so that they could be loaded on IOT devices.

        <h2><u>About the model :</u></h2>

        The application demonstrates the working of a Convolutional Siamese Neural Network. It has been created with
        TensorFlow Keras. Less training period along with simpler architecture are some of the features kept in
        mind while creating the model. Also, quantization helped in reducing the size of the inference model which
        would otherwise diminish the performance of the model.

        <h2><u>Firebase Services :</u></h2>

        Firebase has been providing a number of free services which are scalable and outstanding. The application
        uses Firebase Realtime Database and Firebase Cloud Storage to download the images necessary for the classification of
        Melanoma.

        <h2><u>Training/Validation Data:</u></h2>

        The data was scraped from the web by Shubham Panchal as no such datasets were readily available. The model
        has been trained on augmented images to its best accuracy. The developer tends to extend this technology
        for the classification for more diseases in future. You can use the email-ID which is provided in the
        "Send Feedback" feature to contribute or give suggestions.

        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="what_is_melanoma">What is Melanoma?</string>
    <string name="symptoms">Symptoms</string>
    <string name="treatment_and_cure">Treatment and Cure</string>
    <string name="how_s_it_made">How\'s it made?</string>


</resources>
